<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dsp on John Montroy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dsp on John Montroy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, John Montroy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/dsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DSP 14: Analog Filters for Data Conversion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-14-analog-filters-for-data-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-14-analog-filters-for-data-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covered:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch3/4.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Analog Filters for Data Conversion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Key Terms:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;anti-aliasing filter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chebyshev, Butterworth, Bessel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sallen-Key Circuit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Questions:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How the heck does a Sallen-Key Circuit work?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is a switched capacitor filter, exactly?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is &amp;ldquo;anti-aliasing&amp;rdquo; here similar to the graphical antialiasing setting?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Programming note: we&amp;rsquo;re back! Took some time to see Hoi An and Da Nang with a friend. Happy 2024! May your luck be analog and your emotions only as convolved as you desire.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 13: Digital-to-Analog Conversion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-13-digital-to-analog-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-13-digital-to-analog-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last time we focused on analog-to-digital conversion &amp;ndash; what about digital-to-analog?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to convert from digital back to analog is by reconstructing it via the impulse train we generate from the original ADC process. Then you do a low-pass filter with the cutoff at the Nyquist frequency (all higher frequencies are artifacts of the sampling process), and that should perfectly reconstruct the original frequency spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is fine in theory, but difficult in practice - impulse trains are hard to generate. So instead we do a &lt;strong&gt;zeroth-order hold&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the &amp;ldquo;DAC equivalent of the sample-and-hold used during ADC&amp;rdquo;. This hold generates the staircase-looking effect on the impulse train in the time domain, like so:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 12: The Sampling Theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-12-the-sampling-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-12-the-sampling-theorem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covered:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch3/2.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: The Sampling Theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Key Terms:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;proper sampling, aliasing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nyquist / Shannon sampling theorem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nyquist frequency / rate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;impulse train&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is &lt;em&gt;proper sampling&lt;/em&gt;? A continuous, analog signal is properly sampled if you can &lt;strong&gt;exactly reconstruct&lt;/strong&gt; the original signal from the samples. But this gets subtle! Three out of the four below are properly sampled because the samples correspond to exactly one original signal, e.g. the sampling has captured enough information to reverse the sampling process. But in (d), the last one, the samples do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; represent the original signal, because they can essentially be confused with a different signal! This is called &lt;strong&gt;aliasing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 11: Quantization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-11-quantization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-11-quantization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covered:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch3/1.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Quantization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Key Terms:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sampling, sample-and-hold&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;quantization, analog-to-digital&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LSB&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;dithering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need to convert a signal from analog to digital, e.g. continuous to discrete. That means making both the independent and dependent variables discrete:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We make the independent variable (e.g. time) discrete via a &lt;strong&gt;sample-and-hold&lt;/strong&gt; device, which samples and holds voltage steady at given points at time, like taking a snapshot at intervals. This is called &lt;strong&gt;sampling&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We make the dependent variable (e.g. voltage) discrete via an ADC, e.g. &lt;strong&gt;analog-to-digital converter&lt;/strong&gt;. It essentially rounds each snapshotted voltage to a given level, e.g. quantizing it based on the number of bits used in your ADC - your bit depth. This is called &lt;strong&gt;quantization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantization incurs error in its rounding-off process, with a max of ±0.5 least significant bit (&lt;strong&gt;LSB&lt;/strong&gt;), which is fancy jargon for &amp;ldquo;the distance between quantization levels&amp;rdquo;, or just the step size (0.5 because if you go beyond that point from a level, you&amp;rsquo;ll&amp;hellip;just be rounded up to the next level). We can measure things in terms of LSB as a sort of unit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 10: Precision and Accuracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-10-precision-and-accuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-10-precision-and-accuracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Covered: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/7.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: &lt;/a&gt;Precision and Accuracy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is simpler. When you measure something repeatedly, you get a histogram or PMF. This PMF can be described by its precision and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precision&lt;/strong&gt; is captured by the standard deviation of that PMF - how well do individual sample points agree with one another? Are you fluctuating wildly per measurement, or are your measurements agreeing with each other? Low precision usually comes about because of noise, and precision is always improved by more measurements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy&lt;/strong&gt; is how far off your mean is from the true value of whatever you&amp;rsquo;re measuring. So you might be very precise, but not accurate - that would mean, for example, that you measure 90 every single time, precisely, but your true value is 100. So your mean is far off from the real value. Which obviously requires you to know your real value in advance. Accuracy is usually more a systematic or calibration error, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve with more measurements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;004b14_7e4f8ed29a9b4f229f1333abf3ac06b8~mv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Precision and Accuracy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 9: Digital Noise Generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-9-digital-noise-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-9-digital-noise-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: this fell off - I was just having too much fun in Korea, then Thailand! But now I&amp;rsquo;m back in Hoi An, Vietnam, and feeling good to get back to this.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/6.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Digital Noise Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often need to generate digital noise, which is a random signal that follows the Gaussian PDF. This noise is used to ensure that devices, signals, and algorithms work given the presence of random noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 7: The Histogram, Pmf, and Pdf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-7-the-histogram-pmf-and-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-7-the-histogram-pmf-and-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/4.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Histogram, Pmf, and Pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Histograms show how many times a given value has appeared. This has the effect of &lt;em&gt;batching&lt;/em&gt;, and makes computing statistics a lot easier. So like, mean and standard deviation become:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/004b14_745a186db1314c8e982aee59756b8b87~mv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mean formula&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/004b14_1cffd0723e034f12ae7b344294fdbb94~mv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Standard deviation formula&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here, &lt;em&gt;H_i&lt;/em&gt; is the number of values that have the given value &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;, so like if 100 sample points had a value of 50, &lt;em&gt;H_50&lt;/em&gt; == 100.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 8: The Normal Distribution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-8-the-normal-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-8-the-normal-distribution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/5.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Normal Distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Random noise generates the Normal distribution as its PDF - this was first discovered and termed by Gauss, so it&amp;rsquo;s the Gaussian curve:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;004b14_03f4c8d3a9b64adcb39e010541dd09b3~mv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Normal Distribution&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The standard deviation determines the width of the bell, and the mean says where the curve is centered. Like all PDFs, it&amp;rsquo;s normalized s.t. its integral is one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The integral of a PDF over its domain is known as its &lt;strong&gt;cumulative distribution function (CDF)&lt;/strong&gt;. The CDF of the Gaussian is hugely important, but the Gaussian cannot be integrated through analytical means, instead only yielding to numerical integration where we essentially chop up and sample the the curve and integrate slowly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DST 6: Signal vs. Underlying Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-6-signal-vs.-underlying-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-6-signal-vs.-underlying-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big chunk today! Did a bunch of extra research on basic descriptive statistics I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten over the years. Banner image credit to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@nstatum8290&#34;&gt;NStatum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/3.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Signal vs. Underlying Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ycuPP72_DVU&#34;&gt;The Law of Large Numbers - Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wpY9o_OyxoQ&#34;&gt;Variance and Standard Deviation: Why divide by n-1?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A coin flip as a process has a mean vale of 0.5, where 0 is tails and 1 is heads. But if you flip a coin 1000 times, your mean will not be 0.5. Make sure you understand this difference: &lt;strong&gt;statistics of an actual signal vs. statistics of the underlying process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DST 5: Mean and Standard Deviation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-5-mean-and-standard-deviation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-5-mean-and-standard-deviation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;μ&lt;/strong&gt; is mean. It&amp;rsquo;s calculated as ever:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;004b14_1ab34e704bdd4d979354bc8429cd8e73~mv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mean formula&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In electronics, the mean is commonly called the DC (direct current) value. Likewise, AC (alternating current) refers to how the signal fluctuates around the mean value. If the signal is a simple repetitive waveform, such as a sine or square wave, its excursions can be described by its peak-to-peak amplitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So basic signals can be analyzed with things like the mean, but most signals are complex. For this, we bring in the &lt;em&gt;standard deviation&lt;/em&gt;, denoted by &lt;strong&gt;σ&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;average deviation&lt;/em&gt; is calculated simply, with just summing absolute values of differences from the mean. But the standard deviation squares things, because we&amp;rsquo;re more interested in signal power - &lt;strong&gt;P ∝ V^2&lt;/strong&gt; - so we get:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 4: Signal and Graph Terminology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-4-signal-and-graph-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-4-signal-and-graph-terminology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(note: today&amp;rsquo;s DALL-E prompt was &amp;ldquo;graph with creepy smile in it&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d say mission accomplished)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covered: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch2/1.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: S&lt;/a&gt;ignal and Graph Terminology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Signals display how one parameter depends on another, e.g. voltage over time, density over distance. These parameters can be continuous, e.g. smooth, or discrete / digital, e.g. quantized. Analog signals from nature, like amplitude over time, are quantized by analog-to-digital convertors, e.g. ADCs. These have their sampling rates and bit depths to help. When working with signals, usually both are discrete / digital, or both are continuous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 3: Image Processing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-3-image-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-3-image-processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch1/5.htm&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Image Processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Images are fun signals - they can be signals over both time AND space, which makes them typically much bigger.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original &lt;strong&gt;CT (Computed Tomography)&lt;/strong&gt; scanner is an example of DSP done well. A single x-ray might not resolve everything you need - organs might be blocked, it&amp;rsquo;s a static image, can&amp;rsquo;t differentiate two similar organs - but if you do several x-rays at different angles, you can use DSP to essentially construct slices of a human, which allows you to resolve and probe more closely. This requires DSP, and was a huge boon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 2: Echo Location</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-2-echo-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-2-echo-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three applications for DSP involving echo location:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar&lt;/strong&gt; (RAdio Detection And Ranging): works by firing a pulse of radio waves at an area you want to investigate. If something&amp;rsquo;s there, it&amp;rsquo;ll reflect the radio wave back to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The longer the pulse, the more energy you have, but the less accurate you are. DSP helps here in a couple of ways: return signal compression, filtering noise, and pulse selection and generation. All of this is further aided by samplers that work on the order of megahertz, which is impressive!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Signal Processing: read-through</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/digital-signal-processing-read-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/digital-signal-processing-read-through/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big goal of my 30s, intellectually / educationally speaking, is to finally marry my two great passions in life - music and technology. Despite the obvious synergies between the two, I&amp;rsquo;ve never combined them much beyond a startling command of Finale during college, or passing interests in phenomena like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/sound/Lesson-3/Interference-and-Beats&#34;&gt;beats&lt;/a&gt; and genres like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectral_music&#34;&gt;spectralism&lt;/a&gt;. So it&amp;rsquo;s high time we put them together and see what shakes out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of this effort will be in tools like Ableton and (hello again) Finale, as I try to write and compose. Some of it might be in AI, using LLMs trained for producing sounds (Mr. Bill has some real interesting examples of this). But academically, it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be digital signal processing. And lucky me - there&amp;rsquo;s a book online for just that! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/&#34;&gt;The Scientist and Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Digital Signal Processing by Steven W. Smith&lt;/a&gt; - 600+ pages on all things DSP. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a bit - it&amp;rsquo;s technical, but not insanely so. And seems quite thorough; a whole chapter on linear systems is generous!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSP 1: Roots and Telecommunications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-1-roots-and-telecommunications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/dsp/dsp-1-roots-and-telecommunications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(blog images will always be generated by some LLM or another, today Stable Diffusion)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;_Chapter 1: _&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch1/1.htm&#34;&gt;The Roots of DSP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;_Chapter 1: _&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dspguide.com/ch1/2.htm&#34;&gt;Telecommunications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital Signal Processing answers the question: “What do I do with all these data I just converted from analog to digital?” That can include a huge array of disciplines and industries. DSP used to be very specialized, to oil discovery or space exploration, but once personal computers hit the scene in the 80s, everyone had access to DSP. DSP is one of those fields like electronics - in today&amp;rsquo;s world, everyone working in science or engineering probably should know at least a little bit about it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
