<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Film on John Montroy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Film on John Montroy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, John Montroy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Banshees of Inisherin - something something symbolism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-banshees-of-inisherin-something-something-symbolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-banshees-of-inisherin-something-something-symbolism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, easy Oscar bait, this one. Witty, well-acted, and rife with metaphor and symbolism. A little gross and plodding. Not really a movie for anyone except for &amp;ldquo;film people&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are some dope video essays on how the dissolution of Pádraic and Colm&amp;rsquo;s friendship mirrors the Irish Civil War. Their quarrel is dubiously originated, pointless, and both cyclical and escalatory. Simple slights lead to bigger ones until we&amp;rsquo;ve descended into full violence and no one really knows how we got there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tár - this again?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/t%C3%A1r-this-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/t%C3%A1r-this-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so firstly, this is a much more palatable take on &amp;ldquo;suffering for art&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;art vs. artist&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;power and identity&amp;rdquo;, etc. than Whiplash for me. I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna summarize or analyze the movie - it&amp;rsquo;s been done and better than I could. I liked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v2JAh7kdXos&#34;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r0h2qI1X8j8&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; in particular (I only watched 5 or 6, the others were either light or more interested in hotter takes that have been done to death). I do want to try to articulate a thought I&amp;rsquo;ve had before with content that tackles these themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
