<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on John Montroy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on John Montroy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, John Montroy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Karōshi: overworking in Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/kar%C5%8Dshi-overworking-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/kar%C5%8Dshi-overworking-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first thing I noticed upon arriving in Tokyo, taking the train from the airport at 8:30AM on a Tuesday, was how exhausted everyone looked. Immediately, a younger girl was nearly falling asleep on my shoulder. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I looked it up - it&amp;rsquo;s well-known and well-studied, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be improving terribly quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;karōshi&amp;rdquo;, e.g. &amp;ldquo;death from overwork&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a problem in Japan since at least the 1970s. The government even has a way to qualify as karōshi: if a (likely young or otherwise healthy) person dies from cardiovascular disease (stroke, heart failure, etc.) or mental health (suicide, maybe alcoholism?), and had worked more than 80 hours of overtime in a month (approx. 4 extra hours a day), it&amp;rsquo;s karōshi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>do the things you&#39;re good at</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-the-things-youre-good-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-the-things-youre-good-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/do-the-things-youre-good-at/olomana.png&#34; alt=&#34;Olomana&amp;rsquo;s third peak in Oahu - a hard climb I loved!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a jumpy, climb-y person, as far back as I can remember - even during my short-lived-but-oh-so-intense basketball phase of youth, I was most complimented for my &amp;ldquo;mad ups&amp;rdquo; - suburban white boy slang (and probably beyond) for jumping well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s odd - until very recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve never truly internalized that leg-heavy, jumpy / climb-y activities are truly my thing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to really take inventory of your body in your 30s - what am I naturally good at, what has taken me much longer, what has brought me the most attention and acclamation from others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packing For A Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/packing-for-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/packing-for-a-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m nomading. Packing is fun and interesting. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but here are some takes, mostly tepid in temperature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;High-level takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;choosing clothing&lt;/strong&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m optimizing by, in order:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Space + weight&lt;/em&gt; - you gotta lug it everywhere broh&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Function&lt;/em&gt; - you really don&amp;rsquo;t need more than one of anything, other than socks and underwear. I&amp;rsquo;m consistently gonna be in pretty warm climates, so for shirts, I need one hiking / adventure shirt (moisture-wicking, tough), one (MAYBE two) going-out shirts, and one junk shirt (night time in shared spaces, going shopping, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drying&lt;/em&gt; - you&amp;rsquo;re gonna wash stuff in sinks, bathtubs, plastic tubs, and so on, and you need that stuff to dry quickly! For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased some briefs that are good for this, because my normal sets of briefs are way damp for way long.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renting cars&lt;/strong&gt; is seeming more necessary than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped, but it&amp;rsquo;s very freeing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some things I didn&amp;rsquo;t initially think to bring that are looking necessary:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hand sanitizer&lt;/em&gt; - joins the crew of sunscreen, bug spray, toiletries, first aid, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redoxx.com/flexo-line-travel-clothesline-10103/p&#34;&gt;Laundry line&lt;/a&gt; - washing things on the go is a must, and drying things is tricky in limited space. Having a laundry line to loop around a bedpost or something seems necessary. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this pans out - I&amp;rsquo;m a little concerned about how much space this&amp;rsquo;ll take, and maybe washing machines are gonna be much easier to come by than I expect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laundry detergent sheets&lt;/em&gt; - see above. I probably need travel soap.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quick-drying briefs&lt;/em&gt; - normal cotton-based briefs are not your friend, drying-wise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07DCMNKX1&#34;&gt;Collapsible Tub&lt;/a&gt; - again, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this pans out, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;ll be really handy to have your own tub to wash things in, especially in shared spaces like hostels. Commandeering a sink for 20 minutes to wash your briefs is not gonna make you friends.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I want to &lt;strong&gt;buy things locally&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ll need little things like shampoo, dish detergent, new beach t-shirts, and so on. Why lug my New Jersey t-shirt to Hanoi, instead of buying some local stuff?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating out at restaurants is expensive&lt;/strong&gt;, expectedly - I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get into the flow of supermarkets and shared cooking spaces. Gonna lean into that more.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hate to say it, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://huel.com/&#34;&gt;Huel&lt;/a&gt; is looking pretty attractive right now. TSA lets powders through too. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll POC it in Hawaii.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As an early-30s man who&amp;rsquo;s lived with roommates and alone for long periods, i suspect I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be pretty disappointed with the &lt;strong&gt;cohabitation skills&lt;/strong&gt; of my future hostel / Airbnb friendos. I was a pretty meh roommate myself in my 20s, so it&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my stuff, brought to you by a motel floor in Panguitch, UT, where my stuff is covering a set of stains that was either wine or blood or both:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting to get going!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/starting-to-get-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/starting-to-get-going/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be leaving NYC on 5/1. This is sooner than expected, but probably for the best. My first destination will be Utah for a week of national parks, then SF to say hi to a friend, then Hawaii for waves, water, scuba, etc. This will probably take me to mid-June, and then we get going in earnest to Japan. After Japan, probably Vietnam or Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://vagabonding.net/&#34;&gt;Vagabonding: An Uncommon Guide to the Art of Long-Term World Travel&lt;/a&gt; by Rolf Potts. This is the first travel book I&amp;rsquo;ve read before my trip, and it feels like a good one to start with. It does have specific tips, yes, and the resource lists in the book and at &lt;a href=&#34;https://vagabonding.net/resources/&#34;&gt;vagabonding.net&lt;/a&gt; are invaluable. But the book spends a lot more of its energy on overview, mindset, and attitude than anything else. And for this, I&amp;rsquo;m already grateful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gonna Get Gone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gonna-get-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gonna-get-gone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot happened late last year, professionally (layoffs) and personally (it&amp;rsquo;s, uh, complicated), and I found myself in need of a pretty hard reset around January. I spent two months doing some part time work, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling very good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m leaving NYC on June 1st to travel the world. I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly where yet, but it&amp;rsquo;ll likely start with US national parks + car camping, and then Japan, to go island-hopping. After that, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Maybe Vietnam or Australia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Banshees of Inisherin - something something symbolism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-banshees-of-inisherin-something-something-symbolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-banshees-of-inisherin-something-something-symbolism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, easy Oscar bait, this one. Witty, well-acted, and rife with metaphor and symbolism. A little gross and plodding. Not really a movie for anyone except for &amp;ldquo;film people&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are some dope video essays on how the dissolution of Pádraic and Colm&amp;rsquo;s friendship mirrors the Irish Civil War. Their quarrel is dubiously originated, pointless, and both cyclical and escalatory. Simple slights lead to bigger ones until we&amp;rsquo;ve descended into full violence and no one really knows how we got there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tár - this again?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/t%C3%A1r-this-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/t%C3%A1r-this-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so firstly, this is a much more palatable take on &amp;ldquo;suffering for art&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;art vs. artist&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;power and identity&amp;rdquo;, etc. than Whiplash for me. I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna summarize or analyze the movie - it&amp;rsquo;s been done and better than I could. I liked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v2JAh7kdXos&#34;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r0h2qI1X8j8&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; in particular (I only watched 5 or 6, the others were either light or more interested in hotter takes that have been done to death). I do want to try to articulate a thought I&amp;rsquo;ve had before with content that tackles these themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Got a Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/you-got-a-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/you-got-a-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My legs are strong. They always have been. I had good ups in basketball, was a natural hurdler and jumper, picked up skiing rapidly, drums pretty rapidly, and can pretty easily run for miles at a good pace without much worry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My arms, not so much. They get stronger, but only through diligent, careful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Piano is a lot of arms, as you might notice! And so as I&amp;rsquo;ve increased my piano-playing recently, my arms have had a bit of a rough go with it. The particular trigger was certainly my determination to get better at trilling - a pretty maximalist activity in terms of muscle engagement and tension.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Beautiful Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tiny-beautiful-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tiny-beautiful-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prone to getting deeply enamored - one might say obsessed - with whatever I&amp;rsquo;m working on. My family loves to remind me of my 2nd-grade basketball phase, where I attempted to do:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 jump shots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 free throws&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 lay-ups (50 each side)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;50 three-pointers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dribbling exercises&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;every day. Productivity apps ain&amp;rsquo;t got jack on an anxious brain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, my obsessive tendencies drifted into other worlds - music, programming, video games. I was an upsettingly good DDR + Guitar Hero player, read through C++ books in my free time, was ranked globally in Rock Band drums, picked up real drums in a matter of months, mandolin in a year or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Supposedly Useful Thing I&#39;ll Never Do Again: Python Code Generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-supposedly-useful-thing-ill-never-do-again-python-code-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-supposedly-useful-thing-ill-never-do-again-python-code-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New team, new language, new me. Security + Python. Learning Python is going well, although I don&amp;rsquo;t really like the language for so many reasons. But feeling good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feeling wise &amp;ndash; recent staff engineer, and armed with the tentative insight that what makes me a good engineer is the tendency to ask &amp;ldquo;does this exist? do we need to write code for this?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assigned a new task - an automation platform for cloud operations. Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s do it. FastAPI, OpenAPI, automated tests, boom. Everything is FLOWING. My team seems delighted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
