<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on John Montroy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on John Montroy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, John Montroy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>do the things you&#39;re good at</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/do-the-things-youre-good-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/do-the-things-youre-good-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/do-the-things-youre-good-at/olomana.png&#34; alt=&#34;Olomana&amp;rsquo;s third peak in Oahu - a hard climb I loved!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a jumpy, climb-y person, as far back as I can remember - even during my short-lived-but-oh-so-intense basketball phase of youth, I was most complimented for my &amp;ldquo;mad ups&amp;rdquo; - suburban white boy slang (and probably beyond) for jumping well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s odd - until very recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve never truly internalized that leg-heavy, jumpy / climb-y activities are truly my thing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to really take inventory of your body in your 30s - what am I naturally good at, what has taken me much longer, what has brought me the most attention and acclamation from others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Got a Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/you-got-a-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/you-got-a-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My legs are strong. They always have been. I had good ups in basketball, was a natural hurdler and jumper, picked up skiing rapidly, drums pretty rapidly, and can pretty easily run for miles at a good pace without much worry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My arms, not so much. They get stronger, but only through diligent, careful exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Piano is a lot of arms, as you might notice! And so as I&amp;rsquo;ve increased my piano-playing recently, my arms have had a bit of a rough go with it. The particular trigger was certainly my determination to get better at trilling - a pretty maximalist activity in terms of muscle engagement and tension.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Beautiful Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tiny-beautiful-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tiny-beautiful-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prone to getting deeply enamored - one might say obsessed - with whatever I&amp;rsquo;m working on. My family loves to remind me of my 2nd-grade basketball phase, where I attempted to do:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 jump shots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 free throws&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 lay-ups (50 each side)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;50 three-pointers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dribbling exercises&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;every day. Productivity apps ain&amp;rsquo;t got jack on an anxious brain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, my obsessive tendencies drifted into other worlds - music, programming, video games. I was an upsettingly good DDR + Guitar Hero player, read through C++ books in my free time, was ranked globally in Rock Band drums, picked up real drums in a matter of months, mandolin in a year or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
